Guide to the James E. Boyle papers, 1894-1938.
Boyle, James E. papers, 1894-1938
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
James E. Boyle papers, 1894-1938.
21-10-210
James E. (James Ernest) Boyle, 1873-1938.
13.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, pamphlets, articles, clippings and other material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, pamphlets, articles, clippings and other material mostly concerning agricultural marketing.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Agricultural economist.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, pamphlets, articles, clippings and other material mostly concerning agricultural marketing.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Boyle, James E. (James Ernest), 1873-1938.; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
Agriculture--Economic aspects--Study and teaching.; Agriculture--Marketing.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence with Sidney Adams of Northern Immigration Assoc. (Box 1)
- Correspondence with H.K. Work of Agricultural Trade Relations, Inc. (Box 1)
- Correspondence with S.L. Althouse of Item Publishing Co. concerning AAA and gov't lending and spending program (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Martin F. Amorous on plight of farmer in 1920s and problem of production (Box 1)
- Correspondence with J.M. Anderson, both criticizing new gov't agricultural program (Box 1)
- Correspondence with J.A. Anderson on soil conservation (Box 1)
- Correspondence with M.L. Anderson on farm marketing act (Box 1)
- Correspondence with A.W. Ashby on unsoundness of AAA and Farm Board (Box 1)
- Correspondence with M.G. Bush of A&P on hedging (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Jane Addams ( Nov. 12, 1912 ) on academic freedom (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Walter Weyl on academic freedom (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Victor Wardrope on academic freedom (Box 1)
- Correspondence on Boyle's Agricultural Economics, "Agrarian Movement in the Northwest," "Anarchy on the Farm" (Box 1)
- Reports of American Real Estate Co. (Box 1)
- Lengthy correspondence of Boyle's article on AAA for Atlantic Monthly, 1936 (Box 1)
- Correspondence of Perry Baird showing pronounced Roosevelt feeling among Midwest farmers, 1932 (Box 1)
- Correspondence on U.S. Canadian reciprocity in grain trading (Box 1)
- Percy W. Bidwell letter on rural economy in New Eng. (Box 1)
- Fred Biermann, Repr. of Iowa, letter on form legislation, 1937 (Box 1)
- Much correspondence on Boyle's writings on cooperative marketing (Box 1)
- Boyle's correspondence with Rep. Ralph Brewster on gov't propaganda in behalf of AAA (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Robert Dodge Baldwin (Box 1)
- Correspondence with E.S. Bayard (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Dr. J.S. Booth (Box 1)
- Boyle's lengthy correspondence with U.S. Bureau of Markets while Field Agent in Marketing, N.D., 1916-1917 (Box 1)
- Boyle's arguments with H.W. Caffey on necessity for low tariff (Box 1)
- Boyle's correspondence with Thomas Campbell favoring back-to-the-land movement (Box 1)
- Lengthy correspondence on world grain trade, and letter of Stuart Chase on Canadian grain trade (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Arthur H. Cole (Box 1)
- Boyle's correspondence with Collier's opposing George Creel's crop insurance theories (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Senator R.S. Copeland opposing Roosevelt's "Court-packing" plan, 1937 (Box 1)
- Some correspondence with C.W.A. labor in Ithaca (Box 1)
- Extensive correspondence with Rep. Emmanuel Celler of N.Y. (Box 1)
- Extensive correspondence with Chicago Board of Trade (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Rep. Sterling Cole on Gaffey Acts and AAA and Sup. Ct. fight (Box 1)
- Correspondence on Boyle's Herald Tribune articles on Southern Agricultural education (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Richard T. Ely at Wisconsin (Box 2)
- Extensive correspondence on books Farm Relief and Chicago Wheat Prices for 81 Years (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Frank E. Gannett (Box 2)
- Extensive correspondence with Grain Dealers Nat. Assoc. (Box 2)
- Boyle's letter to Pres. Harding on International Institute of Agriculture at Rome (Box 2)
- Numerous letters to Farm Marketing Act by W.P. Hartman and Boyle (Box 2)
- Boyle's letter to Herbert Hoover, Sec. of Commerce, 1924, on hedging, and to Pres. Hoover, 1932 on immigration laws for foreign students (Box 2)
- Correspondence with James J. Hill (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Senator Moses Clapp of Interstate Commerce Committee (Box 2)
- Extensive correspondence with Rep. Meyer Jacobstein, N.Y. (Box 2)
- Threatening letter from KKK (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Gov. Alf Landon (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Wm. Langer of N.D. (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Wm. Lemke, Rep. of N.D. (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Gov. Frank O. Lowden (Box 2)
- Correspondence concerning milk and egg problems, tuberculin tests of cattle, etc. (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Edwin Mead criticizing AAA and NRA (Box 2)
- Letter to Sec. of Treasury Andrew Mellon (Box 2)
- Correspondence with Sen. P.J. McCumber on Boyle's testimony on Canadian reciprocity (Box 3)
- File of correspondence on Fed. Farm Board (Box 3)
- Correspondence with Henry Morgenthau (Box 3)
- Correspondence with Allan Nevins (Box 3)
- Correspondence with H.T. Corson (Box 3)
- Extensive correspondence on Boyle's N.Y. Times articles 1928 criticizing George Peek's farm policies, and article 1937 on cotton (Box 3)
- Correspondence with Oswald G. Villard (Box 3)
- Correspondence with E.G. Nourse (Box 3)
- Correspondence with Henry F. Pringle on the Outlook (Box 3)
- Correspondence with Rep. Robert Ramspeck on CCC (Box 4)
- Correspondence with several Congressmen on Canadian reciprocity treaty, 1911 (Box 4)
- Correspondence with Franklin Roosevelt as Gov. and Pres. on farm problems (Box 4)
- Correspondence with Rep. Joseph Shannon of Mo. on Gov't in business (Box 4)
- Correspondence with James Shotwell on Canadian-American relations (Box 4)
- Correspondence with Sen. E.D. Smith on cotton (Box 4)
- Extensive correspondence on Boyle's "Ever-Normal Granary" article for Sat. Evening Post (Box 4)
- Much correspondence concerning Boyle's foreign students and his efforts to help them (Box 5)
- Extensive correspondence with Dept. of Agric. officials on marketing problems (Box 5)
- Several Boyle letters to Sen. Robert Wagner (Box 5)
- Correspondence with Sec. of Agric. Henry A. Wallace
  - Carbon copy of letter from Boyle to Wallace, Mar. 11, 1933, congratulating him on his appointment as Secretary of Agriculture and asking if Wallace will permit him to come and talk over economic problems yearly (1 p. yellow paper) (Box 5)
  - Typed letter from Wallace to Boyle, Mar. 13, 1933, saying that he will be glad to see Boyle and adding that the greatest service he can render, as Secretary will be to reconcile "the various forces" to help bring about a national economy which will meet the world situation (1 p. TLS) (Box 5)
  - Carbon copy of letter from Boyle to Wallace, Mar. 14, 1933, sending him a copy of an article on price fixing by George F. Warren and remarking that there is alarm over a report that power will be given to FDR to fix certain agricultural prices (1 p. yellow paper) (Box 5)
  - Typed letter from Wallace to Boyle, Mar. 13, 1934, thanking him for his letter of Mar. 7 (not in Boyle's papers) and saying he is glad to know that he is in sympathy with the recommendations the Secretary made in New York on Mar. 5 (1 p. TLS) (Box 5)
- Correspondence with Sen. Burton K. Wheeler on Farm Board (Box 5)
- Correspondence with Sen. John S. Williams (Box 5)
- Extensive correspondence with Geo. Warren plus clippings (Box 5)
- Letters of Edwin Searl to Boyle, his nephew, and other family correspondence (Box 6)
- Letters of Effie, Eliz., and Louise Boyle and other family correspondence (Box 7)
- Boyle's letters to wife and daughters (Box 8)
- Agricultural reports, manuscripts of Boyle's speeches and articles, published articles, rough notes (Box 9)
- Published articles, newspaper clippings, notes, manuscripts, and loose journals (Box 10)
- Newspaper clippings, articles, notes (Box 11)
- Newspaper clippings, articles, notes, much material on reciprocity treaty, wheat pools, etc. (Box 12)
- Loose pamphlets and journals, newspaper clippings, and articles (Box 13)
- Printed articles, pamphlets, bulletins, manuscripts, and lectures (Box 14)
- Material on Non-Partisan League, newspaper clippings, printed articles, and pamphlets (Box 15)
- Newspaper clippings, notes, photographs, mostly relating to Boyle's travels (Box 16)
- Newspaper clippings, and articles (Box 17)
- Boyle's bibliographical index and notes (Box 18)
- Articles, advertisements, notes, and photographs (Box 19)